[Forging Justice]
[Episode 8]
Mr. Li.
Have they interrogated you?
What crimes are you
and Director Hong accused of?
They've interrogated me twice,
accusing me of covering for criminals
and leaking important state secrets.
Don't discuss the details of the case.
Okay.
We... We will be careful.
Does the crime of covering for criminals
refer to defending Qiao Zhiliang?
Yes.
What about leaking state secrets?
What does it refer to?
What's going on?
I told you
not to discuss the details of the case.
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay.
Can you speak English?
A little.
What kind of state secrets
do they mean?
When I met Qiao Zhiliang,
he was determined to die.
To dissuade him, I told him
the procuratorate
was preparing to
recommend the death penalty.
They believed
that was leaking state secrets.
I'm warning you one last time.
If you discuss
the details of the case again,
the meeting
will be terminated immediately.
Well, well, well...
If we can't
discuss the details of the case,
what are we here for?
Which law stipulates that
lawyers cannot discuss case details
while meeting clients?
Improve your attitude.
If you correct your mistake,
I will change my attitude!
Calm down.
Sit down!
I'll just be standing.
Now,
let's discuss the details of the case.
Is that okay, Officer?
Do you know
Chen Yizhong is also detained here?
Why?
Just wait and see.
Let the storm rage
more fiercely!
More fiercely.
Lu told me about
the process of their meeting.
I think Li Xiang's case is a good thing.
A good thing?
If this case's impact
is large enough,
I think it will be a good
legal education campaign.
It can correct people's misconceptions
about lawyers.
I even hope that
the first trial
can find Li Xiang guilty.
In this way, this case will become
a very classic case
in our country.
But it's too risky.
Even if they win the lawsuit,
their careers will be ruined, too.
What's more, to fight all the way
to the Supreme People's Court,
how long will they have to
stay in there?
If they can't overturn the case,
their whole lives will be over.
What about Yizhong?
I stand by what I said.
The progress of the legal system
requires some people's dedication.
I believe Yizhong is also prepared
to make sacrifices.
You keep talking about
sacrificing Li Xiang and Chen Yizhong.
How's that different from
them arresting Li Xiang?
That's not the same thing.
When they arrested Li Xiang,
they probably genuinely thought that
they were keeping the people in mind
and eliminating threats for the people.
If this case
is only about
saving Li Xiang from there,
then the significance of this case
will be too trivial.
I believe Yizhong's original intention
wasn't like this, either.
He was seeking to fulfill his ideals.
Mr. Lu, who grew up in the city,
probably doesn't know
what sacrifices are.
Cadre Yu,
who are you looking down on?
S-So you're the only one who has watched
Heroic Sons and Daughters?
Why don't you make sacrifices?
I'll make sacrifices when necessary.
Most sacrifices
are made anonymously,
just like dust.
Those who only focus on money
wouldn't understand.
I-I don't understand?
That's right. You don't understand.
The tuition fees
for my four years of college study
were pooled together by the whole village.
I left the village,
but my younger siblings
have to stay at home,
farming the land
and taking care of our parents.
They can't study at school.
You guys can only see me,
but you can't see the people behind me.
To exchange my life
for the progress of the system,
and leave a name in the history
of the Chinese legal system,
I am willing to do that.
He was talking about dust a while ago,
and now he wants to
leave his name in history.
My heart remains
as pure as ice in a jade vase.
Enjoy your meal.
Why did you have to
add that last sentence?
That's the only line he knows.
He couldn't even
come up with the first half of it.
Who knows that the food on our plates
comes from hard work?
If you're not eating it, give it to me.
Hello.
It's me, Ding Zhongxiang.
Regarding the case
of Hong Zhansheng and Li Xiang,
your procuratorate
must make it well-grounded for me.
What?
This might lead to a serious problem.
According to the detention center,
several groups of people have come.
They insisted on
acting as Li Xiang's defense lawyers.
Well, Ding,
these lawyers
are all from the city.
They're very arrogant.
I...
How did the lawyers
from the provincial capital
find out about this?
The provincial bar association
must have told them to do this.
Then how did
the provincial bar association
find out about this?
Someone must have
tipped them off.
Then who
tipped them off?
Well...
Ding, how would I know?
But I think this move
is quite insidious.
How come this mess
is getting bigger and bigger?
Then you'd better handle it well.
Don't let go.
Ding.
I won't take the blame, either.
There's one more thing I need to tell you.
The higher-ups ordered me
to prosecute Chen Yizhong
for the crime of counter-revolution.
Yu Gaoyuan.
Lu Zeming.
I'm going out for a bit.
Go inside.
Stop sneaking around.
What's wrong?
A few lawyers
came from the provincial capital.
They want to represent Li Xiang.
Well, how did they find out about it?
I... I think it's due to
the help of the newspaper office.
It's possible.
Li Xiang is a member
of the bar association.
The newspaper office reported it
to the provincial bar association,
and those lawyers
couldn't just sit there doing nothing.
They usually feel wronged,
and now they are making an issue of it.
What do you mean by making an issue of it?
This is actually a real issue.
Anyway, now Li Xiang's case is not
just about Li Xiang anymore.
Those bureaucrats certainly didn't expect
a small place like Nanyu
would become famous because of this case.
Get maximum results with minimum effort.
Amazing, Lihui.
Wait, wait, wait.
These lawyers didn't mention
releasing Chen Yizhong, huh?
No.
Then didn't he really become a sacrifice?
We need to find a solution.
Comrades.
How about we add fuel to the fire?
Let's go to Beijing
and talk to Zhou Yipu
and Cheng Jianji directly.
They couldn't possibly
watch their favorite student
get locked up like this, huh?
Look.
A perfectly good thing sounds negative
when you talk about it.
There isn't even a charge
against Chen Yizhong now.
Mr. Zhou and the others
might also have no way to intervene.
Ding Zhongxiang
is also troubled by this now.
He doesn't dare to release or convict him.
What did you say?
The crime of counter-revolution?
What are you guys trying to do?
That's why I'm discussing it with you.
I'm telling you, Guan!
If you dare to do this,
both of us will have to bear
historical responsibility in the future.
An immature student
complained a bit,
and now he's accused
of the crime of counter-revolution.
Calm down first.
Calm down.
Do you think he has
a counter-revolutionary tendency?
I know.
How about we find a way
and handle it as the crime
of obstructing public affairs?
What do you think?
After all,
he did break into the detention center.
Are we shopping and bargaining here?
No.
What?
If you really dare to send the file over,
I will definitely reject it.
Even if you dare to send it,
I won't accept it, either!
Ding, let me tell you.
This boy, Chen Yizhong...
Emotionally, morally and legally,
I think he's just a good kid.
Well...
Let's drag it out for now.
What do you think?
Okay.
That's settled then.
I'll go to see Court Pres. Ding
to ask for leave.
Wait a minute.
Are you going by yourself?
How about I... I... I...
I'll go with Yingjie.
You and Lihui can stay here.
Let's make a long-distance call every day
to keep in touch.
[Court President's Office]
Court Pres. Ding.
I didn't answer the phone.
What are you doing here?
Xia Yingjie and I want to
take a few days off
and go back to Beijing.
You're going back to Beijing?
Why?
To report the situation.
Who will you report the situation to?
Our school's mentors.
What a waste of time and energy.
All your behavior
during this one year here
will be written
into your evaluation reports.
It will follow you guys
for the rest of your lives.
Have a seat.
This matter with Li Xiang
will pass sooner or later.
In a few years,
you guys might not even
remember this person.
Maybe in this lifetime,
you will never come to Nanyu again.
But now,
for this person, this matter
and this place,
you are going to
sacrifice your entire lives.
Kid,
saying one wrong word
or picking the wrong side
will ruin your whole life.
There are so many lessons
to be learned from the past.
And this Qin Zhigao, too.
Don't you think he's...
What about Chen Yizhong?
What if he really
gets convicted?
What will you do?
Will you rather die with honor
than live with shame,
or just force yourself
to swallow the bitter pill?
Court Pres. Ding, we're going to Beijing
for your sake, too.
I don't need it.
What did you just say about your family?
I didn't say anything about my family.
The house collapsed.
Xia... Xia Yingjie's house collapsed, too.
Write a leave request.
I'll sign it when you finish.
Listen.
After you two leave Nanyu,
you'll no longer be under my supervision.
As for what you're going to do,
I don't care,
and I don't know.
Nor can I control it.
Do you understand?
Yes, I do.
Thank you, Court Pres. Ding.
Yingjie.
When you get there,
could you bring some books back for me?
If they're too heavy,
just mail them.
I'll pay for the postage.
I'm not in a hurry anyway.
Okay.
Aren't these books
a bit too basic for you?
They're for Zheng Jianmin.
Then why doesn't he ask
Yu Gaoyuan for help?
He didn't ask me to do this.
I'm the one who wants to buy them for him.
I'm warning you to be careful.
From what I've seen,
I don't think Jianmin is that simple.
He's a nice guy.
I'm not saying he's bad.
it's just that...
I know.
I know you're doing this for my own good.
I just think that
he has helped us a lot,
so this is to thank him.
Fine.
You always keep quiet,
but you have strong opinions.
Alright?
I'm taking it with me.
Stay safe on the way.
Okay.
Don't worry. Yu Gaoyuan is going with me.
It'll be fine.
But I'm still worried.
♪ My dear wife ♪
Let's go.
It's time to go.
I haven't finished singing for you.
I'll miss you.
-I'll miss you.
-Let's go.
I'm leaving.
Have a safe trip.
Okay.
Be careful.
Don't worry.
They're not trying to
bring in reinforcements.
They're going to
get their marriage certificate.
You're talking too much.
Rough.
It means violent
and rude.
Firstly,
we need to take a long-distance bus
to the district center.
Then we'll take a train
to the provincial capital.
After that,
we'll take another train to Beijing.
It'll be a bit tiring.
It's not tiring. I'm very happy.
Yu! Xia!
Mr. Qin, w-what are you doing?
Are you going out?
I'm going to Beijing with you two.
I've bought these three tickets for us.
Hurry up. It's time to get on the bus.
You...
Um...
How did he find out about this?
Ask Lu Zeming.
He's so weird.
It's really a bit scary.
It's fine. Let's ditch him
in the provincial capital.
Let's go.
Wait a moment.
So this is Nanyu?
It's just a tiny place,
but it's famous now.
What's the name of that lawyer
who is wrongly accused?
Li Xiang.
Right.
Let's go, Mr. Wang, Mr. Li.
Come on. Let's go now.
Yu.
Here you are.
No, thanks. I don't need it.
No need. Really.
T-Take it. Take it.
Alright.
Enjoy your meal.
Are you hungry?
Let's eat.
[Law Department of People's University
of Political Science and Law]
[Institute of Law]
Let's go, Qin.
Didn't you always dream of coming here?
Qin.
Hurry up, Qin!
[The Spirit of Laws]
The facts are clear.
And the logic is well organized, too.
Who wrote these materials?
Yingjie wrote them.
We all wrote them together.
You guys are good.
You dare to engage in practice,
express your opinions,
stick to your principles
and be loyal to your ideals.
Mr. Cheng and I are both very pleased.
I'm still not mature enough.
I didn't
think through some things well enough.
Who can think everything thoroughly
when they are young?
Gaoyuan,
at critical moments,
you dared to step up.
Good.
I just did what I had to do.
As for Yizhong,
he is just
a bit too daring.
Yizhong always thinks too deeply
about things.
Even if he had not
done this,
we would still pay close attention
to Li Xiang's case.
Isn't this our fault?
Yizhong must have felt
that he couldn't rely on us
and had no confidence in us.
Look at you.
You're
just partial to him.
But the text
is still a bit lengthy.
I'm worried
that the leaders won't have time
to read such a long document.
Come on, Professor Cheng.
Why don't you help set the tone?
L-Let me revise it.
So this document can be submitted
to the higher-ups?
Will they pay attention to this matter?
The country has realized that
to achieve long-term stability,
we must follow
the path of the rule of law.
The construction of the legal system
can't be achieved overnight,
and it should be developed step by step.
When will the instructions come through?
You're even more anxious than I am.
Wait a few days.
The problem is not as simple as you think.
Come on.
Proofread the manuscripts.
Okay.
Let's go.
Mr. Zhou, Mr. Cheng.
This is Mr. Qin Zhigao,
the defense lawyer
of Li Xiang's case.
Hello, Mr. Qin.
Hello, hello.
We're leaving.
Then we're leaving.
Just go.
Bye, sir.
Zhou.
Do you feel that
Mr. Qin...
What's wrong?
Nothing, nothing.
A couple of days ago,
we went to see your three kids.
Your mother-in-law
was taking good care of them.
The civil affairs department
of the commune
has applied for state subsidies for them.
Your kids will be supported financially
until they are 18.
Really?
After their parents' death,
these three children
will be living a good life instead.
Don't worry.
Regarding this money,
your mother-in-law
has to sign her name at the brigade
to get it.
Others can't take it away.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Just eat.
It smells so good.
It's really nice in here.
No one hits me or scolds me,
and I don't even have to work.
Look. I've even gained weight.
Presiding Judge,
now,
my hard days are over.
There's also such a good meal,
and you're saying goodbye to me
before my execution.
I haven't lived this life in vain.
Why aren't you eating?
I can't bear to eat it.
I want to save it for the kids.
Well, regarding this corrupt lawyer case,
why hasn't the procuratorate
initiated a prosecution yet?
They are reviewing the evidence.
But the handling prosecutor has said that
there isn't much evidence,
so it's quite difficult to deal with it.
The suspect has been arrested,
but we have to
delay the trial and sentencing?
It has caused rumors to spread everywhere
in our society.
The effect is greatly reduced.
Regarding this case,
even if we could
barely manage to convict him,
in the future, the verdict will probably
be overturned, too.
By that time, maybe
each of us will be held accountable.
In the end, all of us
will be stuck in an awkward situation.
So what do you think we should do?
Since he has been arrested,
why not let the procuratorate
exempt him from prosecution
and release him?
We'll release him?
Then what about the authority
of the Party and the law?
Considering this point,
I suggested
non-prosecution, didn't I?
Well...
Guan.
W-What do you think?
Come on. Tell us.
L-Let me talk about it.
Actually, non-prosecution
has a deeper meaning.
The premise is that
the party concerned must be guilty.
But after
being reviewed by the procuratorate,
his crime is deemed noticeably minor,
so he is not prosecuted.
But actually, we've both
found him guilty
and spared ourselves all kinds of trouble
that may be caused
by a forced conviction.
Well, I think Court Pres. Ding's idea
is really brilliant.
It's practical and feasible.
It shows both political wisdom
and legal thinking.
In fact, this way,
it's acceptable to everyone.
A few days ago,
our region held a meeting
on the anti-crime campaign.
Among the 13 counties and cities
in our region,
do you guys know
what our ranking was?
You all can take a guess.
What was our ranking?
We ranked 11th.
That was second to last.
It was third to last.
The main reason
for our poor performance
is that
we're not resolute in handling
various kinds of chaos
and dare not strike hard on them.
So there must be a conviction
in this case.
What's more, we have to firmly
render a severe and quick judgment.
Sir.
If we really turn this case into
a wrongful conviction,
and in the future,
they want to hold someone accountable...
I will take all the responsibility.
They can dismiss me if I'm wrong.
What are you afraid of?
Alright then.
Well, why are you
writing this down?
Um...
Does this need to be recorded?
Well, I think this is...
I have it all here. I'm taking notes.
Okay.
He has it all, so I'll stop taking notes.
Did you hear what he said?
He has made up his mind.
Oh, right.
Delete the part about dismissing me.
I didn't write that down.
Sir.
I forgot something just now.
Put Li Xiang and Hong Zhansheng
aside for now.
As for that college student
who has been arrested,
can we consider letting him go first?
Him?
What's the charge against him?
He can't be charged with anything.
After all, he's a top student
from People's University
of Political Science and Law.
He came to Nanyu
for an internship.
Don't let him end up in prison
during his internship.
This...
This wouldn't sound good.
What do you think?
He's been locked up for seven days.
Just consider it as detention.
Teach him a lesson.
Release him immediately. Okay?
I'll think about it.
Okay.
Cheng.
Those kids haven't undergone
in-depth legal thinking training.
It's inappropriate to discuss
the death penalty too early.
Let's talk about it
when they are postgraduates,
okay?
Well,
you really aren't anxious.
Now, because of the Strike-Hard Campaign,
dozens more crimes are suddenly
punishable by death.
Are they all applicable?
If you don't discuss it now,
aren't you out of touch with reality?
Being too eager for quick results
is even more out of touch with reality.
How am I out of touch with reality?
Alright, alright.
Come on. Sit for a while.
Your face is covered in sweat.
Let me pour you a glass of water.
I can't sit.
You... I'm not thirsty.
No need to get me some water. You...
I...
Mr. Cheng.
Xia.
I'm even scared of you now.
You're here to rush me again, huh?
No, we're just here to bring you
the proofread draft.
Yingjie checked it once,
and so did I.
We worked until past 2 AM.
There might be some omissions.
Please take a look.
Thanks for your hard work.
The materials have been delivered
to the central leaders.
They need to
learn about the situation thoroughly
and will handle it very carefully.
Give them some time.
Right.
Mr. Cheng
also needs some time.
Mr. Zhou.
Here. Have some water.
Oh, by the way,
I heard that someone
from the National People's Congress
also submitted this case's materials
to the authorities.
They said the materials
were submitted
through the bar association.
Lihui must have contributed to this.
Right.
Come on. Have a seat.
Don't just stand there.
She's usually so quiet,
but she also participated?
We all participated.
We really don't want to
keep rushing you two.
It's mainly because
we just got off the phone
with our fellows in Nanyu.
They said the county seemed
to be speeding up the process.
We're afraid it might be too late.
What are you afraid of?
Even if he's convicted,
it can still be overturned.
The leaders have also noticed
the flaws in the law enforcement process.
The development of history
has always been like this.
This also reflects
the immaturity
of the current legal system.
Mr. Zhou is right.
Though as you can see, Mr. Zhou are now
drafting criminal law
and compiling textbooks,
during the Cultural Revolution, he was
a reactionary authority.
He cleaned toilets
and was forced into the jet-like posture.
His good friend even...
Mr. Sun.
Hello, Professors.
Yu Gaoyuan,
come out here for a moment.
Let me ask you.
There's a guy named Qin Zhigao.
You know him, right?
Yes, I do. What's wrong?
He was acting like a hooligan
and got caught by the students.
That's him.
He was wandering around the entrance
of the girls' dorm
and acting furtively.
No!
I just stood there
for a little longer,
and then a few boys surrounded me.
I wanted to leave
but they didn't let me go.
If you hadn't peeked through the window,
they wouldn't have surrounded you.
That was the gatehouse.
But you shouldn't have hit him
indiscriminately.
We didn't hit him.
He was like this when he was brought here.
It's fine.
They didn't hit me hard.
Sun,
I can vouch for his character.
I'll sign. How about we just let it go?
No need. Thank you.
Okay.
Sign your name
and take him away.
You guys need to pay more attention.
Don't let this kind of unemployed person
wander around here anymore.
He's not an unemployed man.
He's a lawyer.
With his conduct like that,
he can be a lawyer?
Alright. Let's go.
Qin, let's go.
Thank you.
Let's go.
You can't stay at the school anymore.
The dorm manager has told me
unauthorized personnel
aren't allowed to enter the student dorms.
I'm really not a hooligan!
Nor am I an unauthorized person!
Why are you guys treating me like this?
Why don't you believe in what I said?
Am I a rag?
Qin! Qin! Calm down!
You...
I don't want to say this.
I had thought...
I had thought
if I could come back to take a look,
I would have no regrets in this lifetime.
I really don't want to say this.
Just say it.
I...
I also graduated from this school.
I'm not a hooligan!
Comrade Su!
What's going on?
You guys can't
lock my son up in there just like this!
He's a good boy.
What are you doing?
You guys will be held
historically responsible for doing this!
As for this problem of mine,
I can't explain it to you.
Alright?
Let's go! Let's leave now!
Comrade Su!
Hey, what are you trying to do?
Yizhong.
Help me analyze my case.
I accidentally
cut the village's high-voltage cable.
They said it counts as theft.
Accidentally?
How careless could you be?
Then what happened
to the cable later?
Did you sell it?
Yes, I did.
Since you've sold it,
the nature of this case
is definitely different.
Obviously, you've committed theft.
Yizhong.
Let me tell you about my case.
My girlfriend ran off with someone else.
I went to settle the score with that man.
Unexpectedly, he took out a knife.
I snatched it and stabbed him.
Wasn't that self-defense?
Did you go empty-handed?
I...
actually took a stick with me.
But I just wanted to scare him.
What's more, I didn't strike first.
Your intention at that time...
Chen Yizhong.
Here!
Come out.
Buddy,
congratulations to you on being released.
What are you thinking about?
Haven't you stayed here long enough?
Sign it.
Just sign it now.
Your mom is here.
She's waiting outside.
In the future, no matter what you do,
don't be impulsive.
Everything has consequences.
If you act recklessly,
what about your family?
Sign it.
[Nanyu County Public Security Bureau,
Release Notification]
I'm not a counter-revolutionary man.
Mom.
Look at you.
When you were doing this,
did you think about your father?
Do you know how much injustice
your father has suffered,
and how many sacrifices he has made?
Look at you.
Just for
such a small case,
you almost ruined
your whole life.
If you always act so impulsively,
h-how can you achieve great things?
Your father...
M-My father isn't here, huh?
Your father is here?
Who do you think you are?
Mom,
how did you know I was here?
You... Well...
Let's leave first.
Look at your face.
Gosh.
Which scumbag hit you?
How could he hit you so hard?
I don't know, either.
But who told you about this?
Let's go. We'll talk about it at home.
I remember he seemed to graduate in 1950s.
The Class of 1953.
Here, here, here!
It's here!
It's true.
That's him.
His name is right here.
He didn't lie.
Right here.
Look! Right? That's him.
His...
His appearance has changed a lot.
We weren't in the same class,
so we weren't close.
I remember him.
Back then,
I had just stayed on as a faculty member
and was assigned
to the Teaching and Research Office.
Look.
How about this?
You two can go ask him
who Corzine and Chugunov are.
Just go.
Corzine?
He was the director
of the Teaching and Research Office.
He graduated from the Soviet Union's
Sverdlovsk Law Institute.
He was the graduate students' mentor,
so he had never taught us.
Chugunov
was also a Soviet legal expert
who came here to aid China.
On the afternoon
of June 24th, 1955,
right here,
right in the cafeteria,
at that time,
this place
also served as an auditorium.
He gave us a lecture.
The theme was
Principles of the People's Democratic
Legal System in Criminal Proceedings.
The interpreter on the site was Zhou Yipu.
I remember that day,
it was very hot.
Didn't you see it?
Which department are you from?
The Law Department!
Go to the department
and complain about me!
My name is Qin Zhigao!
Qin.
Mr. Cheng and Mr. Zhou
want you to go over to see them.
Court Pres. Ding.
Our leader has said that
we should eliminate distractions
and focus on the main points.
That college student
has also been released.
Now we should focus our efforts
solely on Li Xiang's case.
If you knew it would end up like this,
why did you do it at first?
His mother traveled all the way here
to look for her son,
bringing some reporters
from the provincial newspaper,
who were holding microphones.
And with the cameras
flashing,
who wouldn't be intimidated?
I heard about it.
I heard judging from
the way she dressed,
she looked like
an educated person.
But when she was making a scene,
it was truly quite terrifying.
Mr. Sun.
If Chen Yizhong
is really guilty of a certain crime,
no matter who makes a scene,
it wouldn't be useful.
Why should we focus on the main points?
That shows a guilty conscience.
You guys are afraid of messing things up
and causing a bad impact.
We've asked someone
to contact the newspaper office.
The article absolutely cannot
be published.
Our leader's instructions are very clear.
The court and the procuratorate
still need to collaborate well.
Seize the time to prosecute
and convict the suspects.
Don't keep passing the buck like this.
A long delay means trouble.
I'll do my best.
Okay.
How did his mother
figure out that
she should go to see our leader?
Yeah.
How about we
look into it?
No rush.
What a smart aleck you are.